Vengeance hits home.
Furious 7 is a action, crime, thriller film directed by James Wan.
Deckard Shaw seeks revenge against Dominic Toretto and
his family for his comatose brother.
Dominic Toretto, played by Vin Diesel.
Brian O'Conner, played by Paul Walker.
Luke Hobbs, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Letty Ortiz, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Roman Pearce, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Tej Parker, played by Ludacris.
Furious 7 (also known as Fast & Furious 7) is a 2015 American action
film directed by James Wan and written by Chris Morgan.
It is the sequel to Fast & Furious 6 (2013), a follow-up to The Fast and the Furious: Tokyo
Drift (2006), and the seventh installment in the Fast & Furious franchise.
The film stars an ensemble cast including Vin Diesel, Paul Walker (in his final film role), Dwayne Johnson, Michelle
Rodriguez, Tyrese Gibson, Ludacris, Jordana Brewster, Djimon Hounsou, Kurt Russell and Jason Statham.
In the film, Dominic Toretto, Brian O'Conner and their
team are recruited by covert ops leader Mr.
Nobody to prevent Mose Jakande (Hounsou), a terrorist, from obtaining a hacking program known
as God's Eye, all while being hunted by Deckard Shaw, the brother of Owen Shaw.
Plans for a seventh installment were first announced in February 2012 when Johnson stated that
production on the film would begin after the completion of Fast & Furious 6.
In April 2013, Wan, predominantly known for horror
films, was announced to direct the film.
Casting showed the returns of Diesel and Walker that same month.
Principal photography began that September in Atlanta, but was indefinitely suspended in November after Walker died in a car crash; filming resumed in April 2014 and ended in July, with Walker's
brothers Caleb and Cody standing-in to complete his remaining scenes, causing delay to its 2015 release date, with other filming locations including Los Angeles, Colorado, Abu Dhabi and Tokyo.
Brian Tyler, who had composed the score for Fast Five (2011),
returned to compose the seventh installment.
With an estimated production budget of up to $250 million, it
is one of the most expensive films ever made.
Furious 7 premiered at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles on April 1, 2015, and
was released in the United States on April 3, by Universal Pictures.
The film was a box office success and it received positive reviews from critics for its action sequences and
emotional tribute to Walker, with many considering it to be one of the best films in the franchise.
It grossed $1.515 billion worldwide, making it the third-highest-grossing film of 2015
and the fourth-highest-grossing film of all time at the time of release.
It also set a record for the second-highest opening weekend of its time.
It was the highest-grossing film of 2015 internationally and became the highest-grossing
film of the franchise in the first twelve days of its theatrical release.
A sequel titled The Fate of the Furious was released on April 14, 2017.
The film explores themes of car race, speed, street race, revenge, race.
The tone is intense.